Here it is.
John Doe.
John Doe is a legitimate name,
Captain Peters.
What do you got?
His wallet was under the bed.
His name was Grubowsky.
Just one more question,
Mrs. Grubowsky.
All right.
I know how difficult
this must be.
Did your husband have
any previous history
of heart trouble?
No.
Anything else?
Among other things,
coronary thrombosis.
Meaning?
A clot in the right
and left ventricle.
Formed by coagulation
of the blood.
Due from extreme exhaustion.
Was he fooling around?
Was he ever.
Like I said, I was
in the room next door,
but I didn't hear anything.
Not a sound.
Are you sure, Mr. Ferris?
Well, think carefully.
Well, except maybe
for one thing.
Well, go ahead.
They left the TV set on.
Do you remember
what was playing?
No, it was after it went
off the air, I mean.
I could hear it humming.
Humming?
You know...
Yeah, yeah.
You remember what time that was?
Oh, about 10:00 p.m.,
I guess.
I don't know.
Anything else?
Sheriff's Department.
No, that's... that's everything.
Well, thank you very much
for your cooperation,
Mr. Ferris.
We know how
to get in touch with you.
They have all
that written down.
Thank you.
We'll be right over.
Bob.
I don't know if it
means anything, but
check the local
TV stations.
Right.
What's the matter?
They just found another body.
Hi.
What can I do for you?
Oh, I'm Neil Agar.
State Department of Security.
Oh, yeah.
All right, it's been a madhouse
around here.
Somewhere in this mess
of bureaucratic garbage
is your telegram.
Sorry I couldn't meet you
at the airport myself.
Oh, that's okay.
Uh, could I take a look
at the Grubowsky file, please?
Oh, yeah, yeah.
Um.
When do the stitches come out?
They're out.
I've been briefed.
They asked me to help
keep you out of trouble.
What happened?
Uh, nothing much, really.
I guess they sent me
down on this one.
It looks like an easy one
after that last one.
That's what I figured.
I don't know what the government
wants in this one for,
it seems innocuous enough.
Well, the Pentagon
likes to keep their eye
on government-sponsored research
facilities, like Brandt.
You know.
Incidentally,
we had another one.
Another what?
Another death.
Heart attack, massive coronary.
I've scheduled an autopsy.
This somebody at Brandt,
Captain?
No.
Kid at the factory.
You think the government
wants in that one, too?
It was there all the time.
A kid with heart failure?
Thanks.
Just one moment.
- Hi.
Neil Agar.
I'm expected.
Okay.
Great, it's through
those double doors.
Thank you.
Can I help you?
I do.
I'm sorry,
he's not in his office.
Michael Levy,
please call reception.
Hey, I'm really sorry.
Gee, this place is
really impressive.
Who's in charge?
I am.
Really?
Yes.
Well, I'm Neil Agar,
State Department Security.
I'm here to investigate
Professor Grubowsky's death.
What can I do for you?
Well, you assisted him,
didn't you,
on his bacteriological
warfare report?
That's right.
Could I see the file, please?
That's, uh, highly
confidential information.
Well, you wouldn't want me to
pull rank on you, would you?
May I see your clearance?
Now may I see the file, please?
Will Mr. Paul Heller,
please call reception.
How dare you
go through my things!
That's just part of the job.
But you were the last person
to see him alive,
and you had dinner with him
on the night he was murdered.
Why do you say "murdered"?
Sorry.
Well, we had dinner that night.
Uh, whenever we work late,
we always have dinner.
Uh, Gretchen knew about it.
- Gretchen?
- His wife.
How convenient.
All right.
You might as well know.
We went to dinner
at the Flamingo Bar and Grill.
And by about 10 o'clock,
we were playing kneesies under
the table, and having dessert.
Like the good old days.
And then we went to the motel.
And then it happened.
What happened?
We balled, and we balled,
and we balled.
Till he dropped dead.
Touché.
Let's go to lunch.
It's a small town,
Mr. Agar.
Nothing ever really
happens here.
So we have to find ways
to amuse ourselves.
We never really get a chance
to get down to LA.
There are a lot of sex games
that go on here.
Wife swapping, and, uh,
a lot of related nonsense.
Scientists really aren't
any different
from the rest of humanity.
Just a bit more inventive,
is all.
Excuse me.
Am I boring you, Mr. Agar?
Oh, I'm sorry.
You were saying?
All of Jack's friends
are notorious Don Juans.
And do you know that from your
own personal experience?
Still doing your job, Mr. Agar?
Do me a favor, will ya?
Just call me Neil?
That's Dr. Murger.
He's head
of Reproductive Biology.
His pet project is the study
of the two-way transmission
of sensory sexual information.
He's quite a loner, though.
I have yet to see him
in the company of a woman.
Kind of ironic
for a sex researcher.
Is he straight?
I haven't the vaguest.
Why don't you
go get undressed?
Okay.
Oh, Eddie, can't you wait?
Jesus Christ!
I can't believe he's gone.
I didn't know Grubowsky
had a bad heart.
No one did.
I'd sure like to meet the girl
he was with, hmm?
At least, there couldn't have
been too much pain involved.
I mean, how would
you classify that?
Accidental manslaughter?
You know what I've
always hoped?
What?
That when my time comes...
Yeah?
...there'd be a few
seconds of ecstasy...
...and then, oblivion.
No, just think about it, boys.
Coming and going
at the same time.
Hello?
Gretchen Grubowsky?
Yes, this is she.
It's very important
we have a talk.
Who is this?
I knew
your late husband very well.
Who?
I was the last person
to see him alive,
if you know what I mean.
I was with him in the motel.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
My husband never...
Don't lie to yourself.
It's very important we meet.
It's a matter of his good name.
You understand?
Yes, I understand.
Okay, I'll pick you up
at the corner of Pine and Hill
in half an hour.
Well, I for one...
I'm going to miss him.
That dumb, horny bastard.
You gentlemen
mind if I join you?
Please, sit down.
Thank you.
I'm Neil Agar,
State Department Security.
Christ, they didn't fly you all
the way here for this, did they?
Well, Professor Grubowsky
was involved in government
research, wasn't he?
I know, but God Almighty,
every time somebody
gets a nosebleed,
you guys run a security check!
Well, doing what you fellows do,
we kind of have
to keep our eye out for you.
But you didn't watch Grubowsky
close enough, did ya?
Uh, you're...
Herb Kline.
Yeah, that's, um...
That's Strategic Alternatives.
Right!
And?
Stan Williams. Genetics.
Stan Williams.
This is Aldo Ferrara, head
of Department of Diagnostics
and Clinical Biometrics.
Glad to meet you.
Thank you.
Uh, listen.
Please forgive us.
You know, naturally,
we're quite upset.
- Jack...
- Thanks.
He was a very special man.
I see, uh.
Oh, I take it, then, he was
a good friend of all of yours?
Yeah.
Very good friends.
It should happen to me.
Who's the lady?
Ballantine's.
On the rocks.
Dr. Susan Harris.
Uh, she runs the comprehensive
entomological lab,
along with Dr. Norstad,
who heads the department.
Hmm.
It's all right.
That's all right.
Let him get an eyeful of her,
'cause that's all
he's going to get.
It's common knowledge.
Iceberg.
Remember, boys, there's
always the six-sevenths
below the surface, hmm?
If anyone can help you with
Grubowsky's preliminary state
of health bio,
Doctor Lyons can.
Good.
It's strange, he said he'd
be here in a few minutes.
Let's wait a few minutes.
I'm sure he'll be right back.
Aloha.
Well, hello!
I didn't see you there.
Thanks.
No, really, it's kind
of dark out here.
Hey, you having some trouble?
Nothing you couldn't fix,
Officer.
It may sound ridiculous,
but could it be
some form of epidemic?
That's a very tough question
to answer, Jim.
Now, each death is
perfectly normal, in itself.
But what about a 21-year-old boy
that dies of thrombosis?
Isn't that just
a little unusual?
True.
But there's nothing else
we can attribute it to.
At least, that showed up
in our autopsy.
You keep talking
about sexual exhaustion.
Harv here didn't even have
a history of heart trouble.
Neither did Dr. Lyons.
Or Grubowsky.
I don't know
what to tell you, Jim.
It's as much a mystery
to me as it is to you.
Great.
Yeah, well, I'm gonna call in
the Public Health Service.
You really think
that's necessary?
I don't think
we have any choice.
We've got two men dead at Brandt
in the last two days.
A little too much
of a coincidence.
Keep me posted,
will you, Peters?
Keep him posted.
I'd love to.
If I knew what the hell
was doing it.
The meeting will
come to order, please.
Captain Peters?
Thank you, Your Honor.
Now as you all probably know,
we've had eight deaths
in the last three days.
I've tried to compile
a list here,
and fix the actual locations of
the bodies where we found them.
Let me see now.
Pardon me.
Yes.
There've been two scientists,
a policeman, a cannery worker.
A barber,
a gas station attendant,
a real-estate broker,
and a grade-school teacher.
As you can see,
there doesn't seem
to be any occupational
correlation involved here.
However, there are
three points of uniformity
I would like to bring out
and underline for you.
One, all the victims
have been men.
Two, all the men have
been residents of Peckham.
And third, they've
all died apparently...
And I'd like to stress
the word "apparently"...
By over-exhaustion in the act
of sexual intercourse.
I've asked Dr. Murger here
to express his opinions to us,
because the possibility
was thought to exist
that some virulent form
of venereal disease
has been responsible.
Doctor Murger?
Venereal disease, which as many
of you are undoubtedly aware...
Louder!
Venereal disease, which as many
of you are undoubtedly aware,
has swelled.
Has swelled.
Has swelled
to epidemic proportions
in the United States
and in Western Europe.
Frankly, I have never come
in contact with, or heard of,
any form of venereal disease
which could result in the types
of deaths we've encountered here
in Peckham.
However, I have a theory
so complex, and so puzzling,
that even to suggest it
before I have the evidence...
Therefore,
in the interim, let me
suggest a course of action.
That a curfew,
possibly sundown, be set up.
Now, let me put it this way
to civic, union, and religious
leaders in this community.
I must stress the importance
of total...
I repeat, total...
Sexual abstinence.
Hold it!
Now, just hold it right there.
This is the stupidest damn thing
I've heard of yet.
Eight guys
are dead from ballin',
and you don't even know
what's caused it.
Now, I agree with Sam here
that you guys over
at Brandt's what's done it!
One of your goddamn experiments
backfired on you, probably.
Well, let me tell you something.
Me, for one, ain't going
to give up what little pleasure
I get from screwing my old lady,
or anybody else for that matter!
Now, if we have to listen
to some more
crazy ideas, I'm leavin'!
All right, all right,
just wait a minute!
Now, nobody is
trying to legislate
or dictate your private morals.
Even if we wanted to,
I don't think we could.
All the man is doing
is coming here
and expressing a few opinions
on how maybe
we could save our lives.
Now, on that basis,
that isn't too much to ask,
you sit down and listen, is it?
You gotta be kiddin'!
What about that up there?
Huh?
He wants us not to have it.
Oh, you gotta be kidding.
What are you gonna do
when you get home tonight, huh?
What are you going to do?
Huh?
Crawl in?
Jeepers.
Excuse me, Stan.
Abstinence isn't going to be
anything new around here.
Well, if I were positive it was
going to kill you, I'd do it.
You know, those queers
over at Brandt,
they must think I'm plumb nuts,
if they think
I'm going to give an order
like that one
to our rank and file membership.
You tell 'em, Barney!
You know, being chairman
of Local 723
may not mean a hell of a lot
to those brains over at Brandt,
but, damn it, at least,
I got a little common sense.
- Yeah, that's right, yeah.
- Showed 'em tonight.
Now, me and you boys,
we've gone along with a lot
of dumb-ass ideas
in these last couple years.
But this one takes the cake.
That's for sure.
Now, those guys,
they freeze wages,
and we gotta lie down
and take it.
Well, damn it, they ain't
going to freeze anything else!
You guys with me?
- All right.
- We're with you all the way.
- Okay, here. Prost!
- Drink it, drink it harsh!
Drink to it.
Mr. Braddock?
Yeah?
I'm Gretchen Grubowsky.
I believe you knew
my late husband.
Mind if I walk with you?
Well,
we're a little early,
but this is where Murger said
he'd meet us.
You know, Freud said,
the idea of dying
during or just after
the sex act
has an ambivalent appeal.
You see, men, for the most part,
have a desire for it,
but, on the other hand,
they fear it.
It's true, like, there is such
a thing as psychosomatic death.
Okay, let's say that the first
two deaths really were
genuine cardiac arrests, okay?
Now, who knows what
dormant erotic fantasies
that would stir up?
You know what we
might have here?
Mass hysteria.
You don't really believe
any of that, do you?
No.
You know, I've never
kissed a cop before.
What's that?
Let's take a look.
Jesus, It's Dr. Murger.
Oh, my God, they're killing him!
Call Peters.
What do you got there?
Are you all right?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Thanks, babe.
Agar!
Yeah?
Any luck?
You'll find a Plymouth,
or what's left of the thing,
where the bridge is out
on the old highway.
- Empty.
- Empty?
That makes nine.
It makes ten.
Ten?
Barney Braddock.
We found him with his
pants around his ankles,
dead of a massive
you-know-what.
All right, all right.
Whoo, whoo, whoo!
Natives are getting restless.
Yeah, I don't blame 'em.
Look, take some of your men
and find out whose car that was,
will ya?
Yeah, I already
figured on doing that.
I know you... you
government heroes don't expect
us local yokels to be able
to do anything by ourselves,
but we get along all right.
Look, Peters.
I know you've got a job.
I got a job, too.
Right.
There are now three men
dead at Brandt.
Hey, Peters.
Peters, I'm trying to say
I'm sorry if I've been
stepping on your toes.
All right.
I'm sorry, too.
We're uptight.
You're uptight, I'm uptight,
we're all uptight.
Really.
They're dropping
like flies, Agar.
They're dropping like flies.
- Great thighs.
- It's got a motor.
It's got a motor in there.
Yeah, hello, operator?
I want area code 202,
State Department 415.
Let's go, Officers.
Everybody! Home!
Come on, now, it's all over.
Yes, call me back here.
Area code 805...
259...
9035.
That's right, 9035.
All right, thanks.
Hey, it looks like
this is going to take a while.
Why don't you wait in the car?
Okay.
Where is it?
In the lot right behind.
All right.
Be with you in a minute.
Hello.
Uh, yes, Neil Agar here.
Mr. Secretary?
Uh, yes, sir.
I'm sorry to wake you up, sir.
Ah, look at that.
I'll take a baker's dozen,
that's what I'll take.
Now.
You gals wanna
play rough, huh?
Is that it?
Get... get her,
get her, get her.
That's it,
she's a cutie pie.
- Don't struggle, baby.
- Don't fight it.
No!
Yeah, come on,
come on.
Yes, I know Murger's death
wasn't like the others,
but that, uh, that doesn't
necessarily rule out a pattern.
Yes, I know, sir.
I... I... I don't know why,
but I... but I'm sure
it's connected with Brandt.
Yeah, all right!
Yeah, get you some.
Get you some of that.
Blow a little smoke at it,
warm it up a little bit.
Mmm.
All right, all right!
You get you some of that?
Whoo-hoo!
Yes, I'd recommend that we
put up a military quarantine
and cordon off this community.
Right, sir.
Well, thank you, sir.
And I'll keep you appraised
of any further developments.
Right.
Good night, sir.
If you manage to do me in,
there's two more fellas here
that'd like to have
a crack at you.
Or maybe they just might
cut you open
and examine you
as a medical phenomenon.
Now, what do you
think of that, huh?
No!
I'll get you,
you son of a bitch!
Neil!
Neil, you can't! Neil!
Stop it.
I have a theory, so complex,
and so puzzling...
Hmm.
Joe.
I was in town tonight
when they found the body.
But when I got over the shock,
all I could think of
was all the letters
he had from me.
The rest is history.
How'd you meet?
I drive a truck at the cannery.
We met at Harm's bar.
He used to come in there a lot
before we, uh, settled down.
Where were you tonight
when Murger was killed?
At Harm's, honest.
I've got witnesses.
I was supposed
to see Henry tonight,
but he telephoned
and called it off.
I was angry.
I was hurt.
So you went over to Harm's'?
And you don't have any idea
where Murger was tonight?
None at all?
He wasn't with a man.
He was with a girl.
I saw them as they drove
through town early this evening.
What she look like?
I don't know.
It was too dark.
She was driving his car,
that's all I could make out.
You're sure, Joe?
Well, what the hell
do you think made me
notice in the first place?
Hey, tell me something,
will ya? Um...
Could he make it with a woman?
No way.
Hello.
Mind if I join you?
Hmm?
Please.
How are you, Dr. Harris?
Susan will do.
Where is everybody?
Locked in their rooms,
I shouldn't wonder.
Being thrilled
at the latest chapters
of the
Phantom of the Rue Morgue.
And you?
Well, I deal in principles
of geometry.
Trigonometry, as in the survey.
I'm afraid, uh,
abstraction is
more Dr. Williams' line,
not mine.
I seem to crave nothing
but sweets of late.
It's too bad.
Well, what's too bad
about it, Herbert?
Well, you know, that's
very bad for your appetite.
You see,
I was going to ask you...
if you would have dinner
with me tonight.
I mean, that is,
if you're free.
Oh, I'm quite free,
as a matter of fact.
You mean, you will?
Well, I must admit
that since the curfew,
Peckham's been
more boring than usual.
But I don't see why that
should apply to us, do you?
No.
I mean, as long
as we're discreet.
Yeah.
Great.
Then, I'll cook you up
something extra special.
No scuttlebutt around here?
Well, there was a rumor
about Julie and him.
I mean, it was just a rumor,
not that anyone
took it seriously.
How well did you know Murger?
How well did
anyone know Murger?
An introverted recluse.
What can I tell ya?
You, um, you going to
Grubowsky's funeral tomorrow?
Yeah.
Well, he was a fine scientist.
Uh...
That'll be the little woman.
Call it ESP.
Hiya, darling.
See?
Oh, oh, oh... n... now listen,
I, uh...
I've got a summary of recovery
operations
tacked up on the board,
so I'm... I'm afraid I'm
going to be nose down
and ass up for another
couple of hours. So, uh...
Curfew?
For God's sakes, Nora,
you're an eternal pessimist.
Relax.
Now, what should happen?
Listen, darling, I've gotta run.
No.
No, don't wait up, okay?
Yeah, tell me later.
Mm-hmm.
Yes, I love you, too.
Domestic bliss, Mr. Agar.
They got to know
where you are every second.
So, where are you off to?
I'm, uh, meeting Julie Zorn.
Oh, cute girl, if she'd
only let her hair down,
much too serious.
Wish me luck.
Good luck.
We're about
to explore the Antarctic
and see what's
beneath all that ice.
Yeah.
There, seems to be
working all right.
Now, tell me again
what it is you're looking for.
I don't know, it's just
something Peters said.
"They're dropping like flies".
It's just a long shot.
Let's go.
Insects
outnumber in species
all the rest
of the animal kingdom.
Insects represent
the highest grade of evolution
among invertebrate animals,
not only in terms of their
complexity of structure,
but also in their
psychic development.
You mind if I smoke?
I'm allergic
to cigarette smoke.
Oh, well, it's just a bad...
Sure you wouldn't
like some dessert?
No, I don't think so.
See, I've got to watch my, uh...
Just a taste?
Well, uh... Hmm, just a...
Mmm.
- It's good.
- Another taste?
Mmm.
The visual organs of insects
consist of compound eyes.
The entire image an insect sees,
consequently,
is a mosaic made up
of as many units
as there are facets
to the cornea.
Multiple vision occurs
throughout
the entire insect world.
The complete metamorphosis
of the insect to its adult state
occurs within the pupa.
Finally, the worker bees tear
open the milky white pupa,
allowing the queen to emerge.
Here, the queen has been
marked with a red spot.
The survival of a hive
depends upon a fertile queen.
Many queens are developed
until one can be made fertile.
During her lifetime, the queen
will lay up to 20 million eggs.
Examples of the female
killing the male during mating
are numerous
in the insect world.
Here, the black widow awaits
the arrival of her mate,
and if the male,
upon sexual contact,
is not extremely nimble,
his fate is sealed.
The female praying mantis
not only
kills the male upon mating,
but even proceeds to devour him.
Similarly, the queen bee
mates in mid-flight.
Well, that's all the material
I have on hand.
Yes?
Mrs. Kline?
Your husband
is in grave danger.
He can't come to the phone,
but he needs you badly.
Who is this?
Just do exactly as I say,
or you won't ever
see him alive again.
Do you understand?
Yes.
There's some sort
of social pattern here,
but I just can't
figure out what it is.
Professor Norstad's the head
of the etymological department
here, isn't he?
Yeah, but he's away in Europe.
Susan Harris is acting head
while he's gone.
I think I should
have a talk with her.
Thank you.
I want you to go on home.
But...
No buts.
You've done enough for one day.
This is Neil Agar,
State Department Security.
I'd like to speak to Dr. Harris
if she's there, please.
This is Dr. Harris.
I'm sorry,
but I'm very busy right now.
Would you please come back
during regular office hours?
Uh, no, it's quite
important that I see you now.
All right.
I'll be out in a moment.
Hello, Dr. Harris.
Look, I have a few questions
I'd like to ask you.
Well, I'm afraid
that's impossible.
We're in the middle
of a very important experiment.
We, Dr. Harris?
Dr. Norstad and I.
Oh, well, then, he's here?
He's in London.
At an entomological
society convention.
I'm working from his notes.
Oh, I see.
Look, Mr. Agar,
I'll answer anything you like,
just please be
as brief as possible.
I'm in the middle
of an experiment.
Dr. Harris,
how many times
does a queen bee mate?
Only once.
Just once?
And only to reproduce.
Once accomplished,
she never mates again.
Yes, thank you, Doctor.
Calm down,
it'll be all right.
Take it easy.
Calm down.
Come on.
You still able to
recognize him as Herb Kline?
Positively.
I'd better go tell his wife.
You feel like coming along?
Uh, no, you take care of it.
I'll be at Brandt.
Hey, what's the trouble?
Military quarantine, sir.
You mean, I can't get through?
Orders are to seal off
the entire community, sir.
But this is... hey, listen,
I've got to chair a seminar
at UCLA this afternoon.
Sorry, sir. Our orders
are quite specific.
No one goes out or in.
Well, this is ridiculous.
Who ordered this cordon?
Secretary of State, sir.
- Captain Peters.
- Mrs. Kline?
Why, yes.
Come in, come in.
May I get you something?
- No.
- Coffee or juice?
Oh, no, no, no, thank you.
Actually, I've got some bad news
for you, Mrs. Kline.
Ah, at this hour
of the morning?
That would be
considered shameful.
Yeah, well...
Sit down, at least.
No, I...
Please.
Uh, your husband is dead,
Mrs. Kline.
Herb, dead?
Yes, we found his body
at the factory this morning.
The coroner should be calling
in about a half an hour
to ask you to identify the body.
Oh.
Well, if I don't seem shocked,
Captain Peters,
it's only because his passing
comes as, uh, no great surprise.
Dear Herb never was
what you would call...
a cautious man.
Uh... I, um... I'm sorry to be
the bearer of such bad news,
Mrs. Kline.
Well...
Well, if there's nothing else
for me to do here, I...
I'd better be going.
No! Wait.
Stay, stay awhile.
Keep me company
in my time of...
...need.
Uh, no, Mrs. Kline...
Oh... Mrs. Kline...
Are you sure you
won't change your mind?
If you give me
a couple of hours,
I'll be able to do
some research on...
Just the man I want to see.
Hey, Agar, what's
with the SS troops?
It's beyond my control.
I've got to be
at UCLA before three o'clock.
- You're the only man that can...
- I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, there's nothing
I can do about it.
Oh, Christ.
Hey, Aldo, talk some sense
into this man, will you?
Herb's dead, Stan.
What?
Like the others.
Oh, my God.
Okay, Agar, give me one
good reason why in the hell
any one of us should
stay in this place.
Calm down, Stan.
Eh, just sit for a minute
and listen.
Uh...
You're the geneticist,
aren't you?
Can you cross a man and a horse?
You're asking me?
Yes.
I told him you'd get a centaur,
mythologically speaking.
Realistically speaking, you'd
get a summons for bestiality.
Come on, Agar, what's
with the asinine questions?
Look. Look, Williams,
I'm serious.
Now, what about
controlled mutations?
We're not ready
or able scientifically
to have the kind
of controls necessary
to alter the complex composition
of genes and chromosomes...
And... and there are
metatheoretical considerations
to examine and...
Hey, with what we know now,
it would still take centuries
of trial and error.
Okay, can you accelerate
the process artificially?
Impossible!
No... Maybe.
Maybe.
Maybe the androgen
and the estrogen hormones
were artificially substituted
by androgynous hormones,
thereby rearranging
the cellular structure.
Now that...
Hey, nobody's been able
to do that before,
except maybe Norstad
and his goddamn bees.
Right, right, exactly right,
Norstad and his bees.
Okay, uh...
I have a theory,
and it's a wild one,
and I'm going to need
your help to prove it.
Hey!
I need some help!
Can one of you guys help me?
Come on!
What's the matter?
I lost my keys.
I can't find them.
Where at?
Over there between
those trees, I think.
You're clutching
at straws, Agar.
That's not science,
that's fiction.
You can count me out.
Williams,
don't be so damn rigid.
- I need...
- Hey, take my advice, Agar.
Go home, lie down.
You're showing the strain.
Bye, Julie. Aldo.
Uh, there is an iota
of credibility in your theory,
you know.
You mean, you'll help me?
What do you want me to do?
I want you to put all of this
in analysis form,
so I can send it
to the State Department.
All right.
All right, I'll go home
and put it on paper.
How soon?
Well, I'll rough out
some notes and dictate it,
Elvira will type it up
for you before dinner...
Um, it'll be ready.
Great.
Oh, uh, one more...
One other thing...
If this forced mutation,
on the energy level
that we're talking about,
did occur, it should be
detectable by a photosensitive
gamma-count synthesizer.
What the hell is that?
It works like a camera.
Mutated cells are infiltrated
with a measurable degree
of gamma radiation,
which registers on a special
photosensitive plate.
Let's try it.
Whatever you say.
And I heard a voice
from heaven saying, "Write:
Blessed are the dead who die
in the Lord from henceforth."
"Yea," sayeth the Spirit,
"that they
may rest from their labors,
for their works
follow with them."
"Behold, I tell you a mystery,
but we shall all be changed."
"In a moment,
in the twinkling of an eye,
"at the last trump:
"for the trumpet shall sound,
and the dead
shall be raised incorruptible,
and we shall be changed."
"For we must all be
made manifest
"before the judgment seat
of Christ;
"that each one may receive
the things done in the body,
according to what he hath done,
whether it be good or bad."
"For we know that
if the earthly house
"of our tabernacle be dissolved,
"we have a building from God,
a house not made with hands,
eternal in the heavens."
In as much as it has
pleased Almighty God
to take from among us
our beloved brother,
we commit his body
to the earth,
ashes to ashes, dust to dust,
awaiting the final resurrection
of our Lord.
Now may the grace of the Lord
Jesus Christ, the love of God,
and the fellowship
of the Holy Spirit, be with you
and comfort you now
and forevermore, amen.
Stan.
Am I still not pretty?
Yes.
I know I've been
a sexual bore,
but I'd like to make it
up to you.
Could I still excite you?
Oh.
Unhook me.
Yes.
Come here.
Oh.
You!
You're part of it!
You and the others!
Stan, what are you
talking about?
Stop it!
Stan!
Julie?
Dr. Harris.
I know what you've discovered,
and I'd like to explain.
It's really, very simple.
I can only guess
at the implications.
I don't think a simple
explanation will do.
Well, perhaps not.
But come to my office...
and I promise you
that what I show you,
you'll be more than satisfied
with it.
You'll be safe.
After all, you're a woman.
Crossbreeding
with other species
produces a superior being.
It's a well-known fact
that thousands of drones
are produced for the express
purpose of impregnation.
Uh, they are ultimately
slaughtered...
Well, hey, Dr. Harris,
what are you doing here?
I've wanted to talk
to you alone for some time now.
Julie.
Halt, do you
have identification?
I have to get to Brandt.
There's a Jeep
down at the end of the line,
you can take that.
Right.
Let me out of here!
I've got to
get out of here.
Somebody, stop him.
What's going on
out here?
Stop!
Don't let him get away!
Stop him!
Get him!
Don't let him get out of here!
Halt! Stop!
Stop where you are.
Hold it. Hold it right there.
Hold it.
Stop him!
Stop him! Stop him!
Stop!
Get out...
or I'll pull this lever,
and Julie will be dead.
Nobody moves.
But I still don't understand
what motivated them.
Well, what Susan Harris
didn't realize
was that the radiation
caused them to be sterile.
So as a consequence,
they were endlessly driven
to repeat the mating cycle.
Goddamn.
You got that?
Is she finished, Captain?
Oh, yeah, well, why don't you
both go get some shut-eye.
I can wrap up things
around here.
Come on,
I'll take you home.
Agar, I hope I see you
again sometime...
...as a tourist.
Like Susan Harris
is a good example.
You know, just stretching beyond
all the imagination of vanity...
to the point where
the mind is even functioning
like in some kind
of a plastic paradise.
Where nothing can really exist.
It's like... uh... the...
Like to relax, for instance,
I use self-hypnosis.
And, like, I know the mind
is like a computer,
if I tell myself
I'm gonna fall asleep
at a certain time, I do,
no matter what.
And I wake up, and I
tell myself positive things.
I mean, it's very...
It's very simple to do...
because all you have to do
is program yourself.
I mean, it's very easy
to relax with self-hypnosis.
I mean, your mind is a computer.
Seriously, how many times
have you tried to fall asleep,
and just before
you're ready to go out,
you tell yourself
you're going to get up at six.
Just before the alarm clock
goes off,
you get up automatically.
I've really become a firm
believer in self-improvement.
I mean, like, after what
happened to me the other night,
there's a perfect example,
I'm never going
to get caught off-guard again.
I'm going to take this course
to improve my body and my mind.
There's either kung fu
or karate or tai chi.
And I will be able to...
In any given situation
to take someone
like you and just
flip you right
over my shoulder.
Just...
No fair, no fair!
You caught me off-guard!
What were you saying?
Oh, shut up.